- Thank you so much for finding time to join us today.
My name is Marina Amini.
I'm gonna go ahead and kick us off
'cause it is 11 o'clock,
but I'm sure folks will trail in from the coffee break.
It's such a pleasure to introduce you to our panel.
I wanna just first acknowledge that Ellie Constantine
was supposed to facilitate this panel.
She had a family situation that pulled her away,
but the guests that you see here today
and many of the questions and the format
really are her brainchild.
So I wanna quickly acknowledge her for that
and thank her for doing that to begin with.
If you don't know me, I'm Marina Amini, as I mentioned.
I've been in the California Community Colleges
for about 15, 16 years as faculty, as a dean.
Now I work for the California Virtual Campus,
which is a course-sharing technology support program
for the entire system, and we support the colleges
with a number of different technologies.
I'm a parent of two students
who went through the California Community Colleges.
One of my students has a disability,
and he just graduated from college, that student,
and he's looking for work.
And so it's been a really interesting journey.
I'm so excited to hear from what our students
will share today and what our industry partners
will share today.
So I'm gonna do some quick bios, introduce them,
and then just stop, Gavin,
so you could hear from our amazing guests.
On my right here is Eden Campos.
She is a lifelong learner, a mother of five children,
and it took her 40 years to get her degree,
and I'll let her fill in some of the details as to why
and what the details of her disabilities were
and how she was and was not served
by the systems of education that we provided for her.
And she is a student of Ellie Constantine,
and she's currently at West Valley College.
She's been both a student and a tutor there.
I'm sorry, Mission Valley College, my mistake, thank you.
And then I'll go next to Jessica,
our other student sitting on the far end to my right.
Jessica Lopez, she has an amazing bio,
but I just wanna say, in my mind,
I just think of Jessica as like an influencer.
You know? (laughs)
I don't know if that's what you are.
That's kinda how I came about Jessica online
is she is a social media influencer and star
and expert on many, many topics,
but she is currently an honor student
at Arizona State University ASU,
completing a bachelor's degree in business administration,
and she's going to be graduating this December
with summa cum laude, and that's pretty exciting.
She worked as a corporate marketing intern at Amazon.
She has also had a number of other amazing positions,
including earning a scholarship
from the Obama administration,
a LinkedIn position as well,
which I'll let her talk more about.
The way I kind of became acquainted with Jessica
is on LinkedIn.
She is an enormous advocate for online education,
and the benefits and access that it opens
for students with disabilities,
and online education is my life.
So that was really our point of connection.
I have followed her growth tremendously,
and I'm really, really impressed by her contributions
to our field and to our work and to the support
that we provide for our students with disabilities.
Here next to Eden is Eddie Lin.
Eddie started his career at UBS Investment Bank
and Goldman Sachs in New York,
and then he moved to LA for business school,
where he transitioned to marketing at Adobe in San Jose,
so lots of partner names there that you've heard.
After getting his Master's of Business Administration MBA,
Eddie competed as a contestant on,
you ready for this, "Fear Factor."
Y'all ever, did you eat spiders,
or like, we'll hear more about that in a bit.
Actually, no, he ate 20 live bees.
True, truth, I can't make that up.
And then he joined the entertainment industry
in strategy and business development,
and actually, he now serves as adjunct faculty
at Cypress College, and he founded Nexus Edge Education,
which focuses on creating greater access
to economic opportunity, and I'll let him talk more
about Nexus Edge and his contribution
to that field in a bit.
And then next to Eddie, we've got Keelan Schule.
He is an innovative technology leader
and solutions engineer at OpenAI,
and he specializes in AI-driven learning solutions
within higher ed.
He collaborates with institutions
to enhance curriculum development,
personalized learning experiences,
and streamline campus operations.
And previously, he spent 12 years in enterprise sales.
He is a father of two, and he's married
to a primary care physician, which I thought
is a really cool part of your bio as well.
So let's give a round of applause
and welcome my amazing panelists here.
(audience applauding)
And although I have covered a little bit about the bios,
I would love to give each of them a couple of minutes
to just talk about their background, who they are,
and a little bit about their organizations as well,
if they're representing an organization
or about their student journey.
So I'll start with Eden.
Go ahead, Eden.
- Good morning, everyone.
I'm Eden Campos.
I'm gonna be reading off my, what's that, my paper?
It's a product of ChatGPT.
And it was the very first time I used it.
I have no experience with this AI.
And so because of my disability, I can ramble.
I have time blindness, but I'll read off this first
and you'll have a little idea of what I'm going through.
Hello, everyone.
My name is Eden Campos.
I'm currently working as a tutor
with students with disability
at Mission College here in Santa Clara.
I'm also a licensed vocational nurse.
My journey on how I became a nurse
is another story for another time.
My own path to education has been anything but easy.
It was utmost challenging.
It actually took me three attempts
and nearly 40 years to get a degree.
Along the way, I faced both physical
and invisible disabilities.
I live with learning and processing disabilities,
which include inattentive ADHD
and a little known disorder
called disorder of written expression and other diagnoses.
And this, I was diagnosed at the age of 53.
So you can imagine not knowing throughout those years,
am I crazy?
What's wrong with me?
Let me tell you about my disability.
For me, putting my thoughts into written form
is one of my biggest challenges.
It can take up to four hours to put my thoughts into words
and then put it into written form,
whether paper or on the computer.
I always felt defeated, but I never gave up.
So if it's just a paragraph,
you can imagine what it is with an essay,
which is five paragraphs.
So, but I said, I got, there has to be another way.
And thank God there's technology now.
With persistence and perseverance,
I graduated last year.
So thank you. (audience applauding)
With honors as summa cum laude
with my Associate in Arts degree.
Now I use my experience to support students
who also struggle, reminding them that success
isn't how fast you get there,
but it's about not giving up on yourself.
I'm honored to be here today to show you,
to share with you my thoughts,
insights, and experiences with you.
(audience applauding) - Thank you, Eden.
- Good morning, everyone.
I'm Eddie Lin.
I'm gonna give my take from the workforce side of things.
So as Marina mentioned, most of my experience
comes from industry and Fear Factor.
And in 2016, Cypress College asked me
to be an adjunct faculty.
And then I realized about half my students
could have been my colleagues at Golden Saks.
And we said, how do we prove that?
So went back to old colleagues
and the CEO of Citi Venture Capital at the time,
her first job out of her PhD at MIT
was a middle school biology teacher in New York City.
And so we said, all right, let's put together a program
where we put together training materials
from Citi Group into Canvas.
And then faculty have been able to add those materials
from Canvas into their class.
And students that passed those materials
were able to get interviews with Citi.
So part of this whole thing
is democratizing access to opportunity,
creating greater access.
And so if you can do the job, you should get the job
and aligning classroom instruction
with what industry is looking for.
Turned out those students were the very first ever
investment banking intern at JP Morgan
without a four-year degree,
Morgan Stanley Software Engineering,
Citi Group Risk Management.
That laid the foundation of these AI programs
that we just finished and are continuing.
So about three months ago,
we had a program with HubSpot, it's like Salesforce.
And they have an AI program where we asked HubSpot,
it was like, well, what sort of skills
do you want students to learn right now?
And they said, well, we have our AI products
for automatically generating blog posts,
social media posts, and podcasts.
And so we integrated that into Canvas.
We had faculty at 48 California community colleges
add that to their Canvas shells
as part of their curriculum.
Students, 300 students were able to get internships
with HubSpot clients, and they all learned AI skills.
Some of them continued in their internships
following graduation.
And after that, that set the foundation
for a Google AI program right now,
where we've integrated introductory LLM models
and Gen AI models and AI Studio,
where students generate images, other media, and apps
just with a few lines of text.
And the top 35 students there will receive a stipend,
and that kicks off in about four weeks.
And all those materials are in Canvas as well.
So anyway, to recap everything,
we're using Canvas as a delivery channel
to align industry training with classroom instruction,
and also as a recruiting channel
so that students can get the latest AI roles,
reducing bias in hiring.
So sorry that was a bit long, but all right.
- Thanks, Eddie.
And now we're gonna hear from Keelan.
- Hey, my name is Keelan Schule.
So I'm a solutions engineer from OpenAI.
It's a really unique position,
and I focus on K-12 through higher education.
I get to go on site to campuses
and basically teach everybody how ChatGPT can be used,
how the models can be used,
and how to sort of integrate that
like with the education journey.
My journey to this position, though, is kind of atypical.
I work in Silicon Valley, but I was a rural farm kid
from middle of Canada growing up.
I graduated from bioinformatics at
the University of Saskatchewan
and then migrated down to the US a couple years back.
I've been in sort of the enterprise technology space
for a long time,
and this is what introed me into AI a couple years back.
I have now two kids, and that was like now my driver
to wanna influence the education space.
So my youngest, or oldest right now,
just entered grade one.
And the thought of like knowing
that her entire educational journey is gonna be altered
because of this new technology is fascinating to me,
and I wanna influence that as much as I can
in like a very positive way.
So that's kind of why I'm here
and the driver for me being here.
- Hi, everybody, I'm Jessica Lopez.
I am a student.
I was born without hands and feet, as you can see,
but I also developed a chronic illness
when I was 10 years old
that is not related to my physical disability,
which completely changed and altered the course of my life.
Before I became chronically ill,
I was at a performing arts school.
I did singing, dancing, and drama.
I was very physically active.
I used to ride horses,
and my chronic illness completely stopped all of that.
And so I ended up graduating high school
four years later than I should have because of that.
The only reason why I was able to graduate
was because of the advancement
of online education in COVID.
I was able to complete two years of high school
in less than four months
because I was able to study online,
study at a pace that is more efficient for my body
and log off, and I'm not able to do that.
And that completely changed my life.
I found Coastline College,
which is an online community college,
and really was able to kind of expand my opportunities.
I became president of student government,
really advocating for the advancement of online education
and making sure that it doesn't disappear
as we go further and further away from the pandemic.
I graduated with three associate degrees in two years
in business, economics, and communications,
and then I transferred to Arizona State,
which is also online,
where I'm advocating for disability inclusion in general
and making sure that any technology that we use
is benefiting people with disabilities
and making sure that people with the most rare disabilities
can still access things and have the same opportunity
that I was able to get myself
as a result of systemic barriers being eliminated
through just the way society decided
to operate within COVID.
So yeah, that's a little bit about me.
- And I just wanna... (audience applauding)
I just wanna emphasize something from Jessica's bio.
She got three associate degrees in two years.
I mean, it's phenomenal. (audience applauding)
And with the right opportunities, right?
The right opportunities,
like having the online education available to her
during COVID to catch up on her education.
So these are really critical things.
My next question is for our students a little bit more.
I'll start with Eden.
Eden, you talked a little bit about your disability.
Can you talk a bit about
what are the challenges you faced in your coursework?
I know you mentioned writing.
Just as a quick preface to that,
I just met Eden in facilitating this panel
and I needed a bio from her
and she was struggling to write.
I didn't know about her disability.
And so she was struggling to write that bio
and then she called me and we had a 20-minute conversation
and I got everything I needed from her.
But previous to that, she told me she spent three
or four hours trying to put together a written bio for me.
And I had asked her something,
not knowing of that disability,
but really this alternate form was quicker
and it was satisfactory.
So Eden, tell me a little bit more,
tell us a little bit more about the challenges you faced.
- When I first started my college journey,
it was way back in the '70s.
And at that time,
I don't think there was even a word of accommodations.
And I struggled with that.
Unfortunately, it was futile.
That's how I got my nursing degree.
I was one course short of getting my bachelor's degree.
So I left because nobody understood
because they thought, you know, it's in your mind.
You know, that's what my professor said, time management.
But if you think about what ADHD is,
that's disorganization and all that.
And this newly diagnosed for me
was the disorder of written expression.
Then a couple of years later in the '90s,
now I think it became a word.
And fortunately, I came across a blurb
on a school schedule from De Anza that just said,
do you have problem taking notes?
Do you have problems processing?
And that opened my door.
And I went to the learning center and I got diagnosed.
I mean, well, they told me that there was something there,
which I think is an eye-opener
because many of our students don't know
that they do have a problem.
And I think it's important also for administrators,
maybe just put a blurb in your ads
to at least go to the DSPS or your disability services
to at least have a student inquire,
is there really something wrong?
Then after that, unfortunately,
due to other circumstances, I had to stop.
And then my third chance was admission.
And that also opened doors
because by now, technology kind of caught up.
And that's when I learned about the SmartPen,
which helped me, okay, I don't have to,
because I also have an auditory,
what's that, processing problem.
Just listening and writing,
I can't do that at the same time.
So with the SmartPen, that opened another doors.
And then another technology was CurseWild
because I have difficulty in looking at white print.
So there's the dark screen and all that.
Other than that, so with all these disabilities
that I have encountered now,
I also been able to use that knowledge
for tutoring my students with the disabilities.
I'm known to be very patient.
And that's the thing about the invisible,
the intellectual disability.
Nobody knows.
If you talk to me, you wouldn't have known.
Even like Marina, she wouldn't have known
unless I disclose it.
And so amongst your students,
I think we have to be kind of intuitive
as to if you're in class,
why is this student struggling?
Why are their grades not up to par?
They may not know it,
but you can at least give them an opportunity for that.
Another thing before, I have a student
and this is with talking about maybe policies.
Students nowadays, especially like with English,
like in English where they have to write an essay.
A lot of our students are using either chat GPT
or just even text, what's that, text to speech?
Oh no, speech to text.
This student is so afraid of putting what was on the phone
because of, am I plagiarizing?
Because I go, well, that's part of your accommodations.
And they said, but my professor says I can't use that.
So imagine with that student,
that's the only way that student can express themself.
So please keep in mind that there are,
maybe when you have policies and stuff that there are,
even with older adults, we struggle too.
So keep that in mind.
Thank you.
- Thanks, Eden.
And Jessica, tell us a little bit about,
obviously you've talked a little bit
about your physical disabilities.
Even coming here today, we were like,
is there gonna be a ramp in the room for her to use?
What is the seating situation?
Where is the elevator?
These are obvious questions that you have to navigate.
But tell us more about the coursework
and some of the experiences you've had there.
- Yeah, I think one of the biggest challenges
for online education is you're kind of by yourself.
And I think a lot of that is the way professors
see online education.
They think of it as like Netflix.
You just go and consume content,
and then you do your homework by yourself,
and that's how you learn.
But there is a wide variety of platforms
where you don't have to be learning by yourself.
You can use Zoom, you can make your classes synchronous
instead of asynchronous.
And that's really important in core subjects
where it can be really challenging for a student to learn,
like math or English.
For me, my hardest subject was math.
And so when I was an online student,
it was very challenging for me to just read a textbook
and make it make sense.
I had too many questions and nobody to ask.
I could email my professor
and ask him clarifying questions,
but I need those answers right now
while my brain is in that mode and I can understand it,
not his delayed response three days later.
And I think that's one of the most important things
about online education is that there's a way
of having office hours where people can drop in
or having synchronous Zoom sessions every week.
Even if your class is asynchronous, still offering that.
My best professors did that,
especially I took remedial math.
I was really nervous about that
because I do know what online education is like,
but my professor would teach us three
hours a week over Zoom
and I was able to learn that way.
But in classes where I wasn't able to have that,
I love with ChatGPT to be like,
this is statistics and I don't
understand this math problem.
ChatGPT, can you answer my questions?
And it would really help me
kind of figure out these math problems
and show me why do I take this path for this math problem
versus that path for another problem.
And so I think that's really important
is leveraging all the tools together
to make sure that you're building a classroom
that is holistic and also thinking about
how disabilities go into it as well.
When I was younger, captioning was not really a thing
I'm hard of hearing and so I need captioning
in order to kind of keep up and follow.
But like when I was younger and like if you watch TV,
captioning wasn't really available.
But over time as things have gone more progressive
and especially AI has been around,
captioning is more widely available than ever before.
And so professors can leverage AI tools
to create captioning that is accurate
and can show the inflection point of people's vocals
and give all that context of people
who are hard of hearing who need that.
And I appreciate my professors who put that effort into it
because I do know it takes time
but that makes the difference
between a student who can actually learn
and a student who has to dump their class
and try to find another professor
willing to give them what they need.
- Thanks, Jessica.
All right, so Keelan and Eddie,
you've heard Jessica and Eden talk a little bit
about some of their challenges.
Where do you see industry partners coming in
potentially using AI to support some of these needs?
- The first thing that comes to mind is personalization.
And what you brought up that bringing a lot of tools
coming together is super important.
I get a chance to go to a lot of campuses around the US
and sort of hear from teachers, professors,
what are they trying to solve and what can they help with?
And a lot of it comes down to that there's edge case
where students can't either understand the curriculum,
they can't interact with it.
And that's where AI can really make a huge play.
About three years ago when it was only text-based,
it didn't really do as much.
But now that you can talk to the models,
you can send images to the models,
you can generate captions, translation between languages,
there's so much that can be used for
to really kind of close the gap
to make any learner be able to manipulate
the curriculum a little bit to better suit their needs.
'Cause I think a lot of course material
is sort of like a retrofit for accessibility after.
So here's material and then we'll add in things
to make it accessible for everybody.
But if we can have AI in the beginning,
I think it changes that a lot.
And now it doesn't put the onus on just like faculty
to alter the curriculum,
but now students have tools to better understand
and interpret and be able to work with that.
And I think it's that the real kind of benefit
or the win there is that students don't feel
like they're an exception anymore,
that the course is built with them in mind.
And I think if we can have AI
inside of the course material early enough,
that's really what it changes.
Another part that we hear is around using technology,
not so much just using AI to understand course material,
but let's say you got assigned an online course
and you've never been logged into Canvas before.
You can use like ChatGPT to tell you how to use Canvas
in order to learn the material.
So like these steps along the way
of not just learning the material,
it's really, really beneficial for any learner,
regardless of like what it is
that they might struggle with.
It could be executive function
or some other kind of form like that.
But those are some pretty big areas that we hear a lot.
And a really big part of that is like,
how do we like personalize that learning experience
to like allow that student to really drive their journey?
- I really like your comment on personalization too,
especially because one of the challenges
that Jessica outlined is maybe one
that we don't think about with disabled students
who are taking online classes,
which is a little feeling of isolation, right?
And feeling that you're just sort of
this added on person in a classroom.
So I appreciate that.
- Yeah, and on the workforce side,
we're in an era where five lines of natural language text
has really closed the gap between jobs
that were considered very high paying
and those who were just entering the workforce.
For example, we had that program mentioned with HubSpot.
There was a student from Irvine Valley College,
19 years old.
The company he was interning for,
they replaced their digital marketing agency with this kid.
And they started paying him $330 an hour at 19.
They capped him at $10,000.
But he essentially replaced a UI/UX designer,
an expert in content for cybersecurity,
and another web designer.
And so yeah, AI is going, it is,
he didn't have to be an expert in any of those areas,
but he knew how to write those prompts.
That's five lines of text, really.
And apps are being developed using AI Studio,
using Google Gemini now too.
So students with disabilities,
with speech to text, anything like that too,
and even if you have ADHD,
the prompts, they suggest prompts for you
to help clean that up to write really effective apps.
So now, I don't know if you've played
with any of those app generation things,
but you can launch an app with five lines of text,
go get some coffee, come back,
and you'll have an AI app already done for you.
And this has already been done
within the California Community College system
that we've deployed.
So now, you have a whole variety of high-paying roles
that are available to students now
to close the gap between those with 20 years of experience.
So I guess, for all of us in the room,
let's be happy that all of our students
have the opportunity to receive really high-paying jobs.
For folks with 20 years of experience,
I guess better learn those things.
So that's where we are in the age of generative AI
and the jobs that are associated with them.
- If I can add to that,
as the students are entering their career journey,
there's a big gap tended to be
where interviewing skills isn't there or role-playing.
So if I'm going to business school,
I wanna get asked questions back and forth.
How can I do that?
And let's say if you have somebody
that's from a business school
that can actually do your own questions,
you tend to print paper, answer them down there.
It's not really a realistic scenario.
And now, with the ability to talk to the models,
and you can create a custom GPT with instructions
that says a persona.
So that's an interviewer for Goldman Sachs,
and I'm gonna be interviewing for this position.
Ask me questions as if that persona.
That sort of angle, I think,
really accelerates individuals
to be able to get into their career a lot faster
than they otherwise would.
It just really prepares them ahead
that they would've never been able to do before that.
- I do wanna add to that
'cause it's such an excellent point, too,
is the number of students
that would ask me for interview tips,
it was not scalable.
And if you look at the ratio of students
to career services advisors,
it's like 30,000 to five, right?
So it's not possible.
But because of speech or text,
we are actually putting this
on our development timeline right now, too,
is that you can actually record yourself
with so many of those video tools now
answering those predefined interview questions,
and that can be transcribed into text
that we feed into our Gemini model
that comes up with personalized suggestions
back on how they can get feedback
to their specific interview questions
at their specific companies.
And that's helped a lot of students with disabilities
'cause often they're a bit too shy to say,
"Hey, you know what?
"They're afraid to come out for help."
If you're just sitting in the comfort of your own home,
just recording yourself and watching the text come back,
you can create a level
of personalized interview improvement
that wasn't possible before.
So that's helped a longstanding issue
both within career services
and provided an opportunity for students with disabilities
to get feedback that they wouldn't normally seek out.
- Can I ask a clarifying question about that?
So my son, as I mentioned, graduated,
he has a degree in computer science,
but he's on the spectrum,
so he really struggles with social skills.
And the interviews are really tripping him up.
He feels really unprepared.
So I love hearing some of the preparation.
Now, I get the prompts and I get the questions
and posing as an interviewer, that's great.
Will the AI also provide feedback on like,
make more eye contact, don't nod your head a lot,
turn your shoulders to face the person,
don't make noises,
because sometimes there's just noises
or clicks that people make,
like is that something that the machine
can help the human with?
- It actually, it can now, which is pretty fascinating.
So if you have like chatty between your phone
and you click on this voice mode button,
you'll see a little camera icon
and the camera icon now sends video.
And basically it sends like frame by frame
to the models to assess it.
So really quick movements that might not capture,
but the general body language of like sitting upright
and being slouched, hand-eye coordination,
that kind of stuff it can generally pick up on
and can really like guide that person through it.
Kind of a fun, so last night in my hotel room,
I was talking to my chatbot on these questions
'cause I wanted to like run through them.
And I had the video on as well
and it gave me some tips of like,
you know, looking at audience members.
So I think it can really kind of drive
like those social personal skills
that it's kind of struggling
unless if you've been through it a lot,
you don't know how to learn that.
- Okay, so my next question,
I'll take it back to the students.
I mean, you've heard about these great tools
and resources available for students,
thinking about your own journey, right?
Because you've gone through the community colleges
and you're both now in the workforce as well,
you're making a living.
What sorts of things do you wish were in place
for you earlier in your journey from the get-go
to enable your success as a student?
Eden, go first, please.
- I wish I had all of this, you know,
because as I said earlier,
I mean, from the '70s to the present,
you know, it's just like overwhelming.
And especially with older adults,
I have, you know, with my students too,
just even getting, you know, online on Canvas is daunting.
And there really isn't, you know,
maybe there's a tutorial,
but then after that, it's like, where?
So, you know, I think maybe in part of the curriculum,
you know, maybe in the beginning of the,
you know, your first day, say,
okay, those who have problems with Canvas
or whatever system you use,
you can find, we have a tutorial, you can find it.
They are offering workshops,
but not everyone can go to the workshop.
So have that as a facility for students.
Also, you know, as I was going through attending this,
I had no experience at all,
or even I'm intimidated with AI.
And I go, how does this work?
You know, I'm, it was funny the other day,
someone said about,
I'm from the generation of Arnold Schwarzenegger Terminator
about what they're gonna do.
But, you know, after talking to a lot of people here,
I kind of eased in.
And that's why I was amazed my very first time
with my introduction.
And I said, oh, I wish I had this.
And then I, and with this knowledge,
I can, I will be able to help my students.
And with the information that Keelan gave,
it was like, wow, it's just mind blowing.
So, but the, you know, as I said,
it's also, you know, in the school,
you have to, you know, let's keep up with the times.
Is a lot of, you know, a lot of schools, yes,
haven't gone up or haven't accepted it yet.
And this information I found out from the pre-conferences
that a lot of schools, colleges have not been on board yet.
So, you know, it's time to help, you know, our students.
- And I just wanna clarify,
when she says it's my first time using it,
like literally she just started using ChatGPT
like yesterday, this morning, okay.
And if you came in a little bit later,
you missed her describing that it could take her
like four hours to write a paragraph.
That's part of her disability.
And so she was able to put the questions
that I had given her in advance into ChatGPT
and it helped her to write out some of her responses
to keep organized.
So that's sort of what she's talking about.
Literally between our call on Sunday and today,
you learned to use ChatGPT, fantastic.
- As my problem is with time management
and part of ADHD is what they call time blindness.
I think a lot of people with ADHD,
it's a time blindness is I have no orientation.
Maybe that may also be a problem
with some of your students that are chronically late.
I can prepare, you know, at six o'clock for my class
that's at 10 o'clock and I am still late.
I don't know what.
And a friend of mine said real quickly,
she says, "Eden, what's taking you so long?"
I go, "I'm going as fast as I can."
No, you're in slow motion.
People perceive in me, they see a slow motion.
For me, I am just all over the place.
So just a heads up on that.
- Thanks Eden.
Jessica, tell us a little bit about your journey
and what you wish was in place maybe from the beginning.
- I think one of the things that people might be surprised
to hear about me is the fact that
I didn't consider myself disabled.
You look at me and I'm probably the most disabled person
you'll ever think of, right?
I don't have hands and feet, it's very visible,
you use a wheelchair, there's a lot of limitations,
what can you do, what can't you do?
But I didn't consider myself disabled.
I thought of myself as somebody who's like,
I'm not limited by whatever it is that I can do.
I can write physically, I can draw,
I can do all those things independently.
And I learned to come into my identity
as a person with a disability and not
see it as a bad thing.
But it took a long time to get there
and it took a lot of negative learning
of what disability is through all of our life,
just the narrative that we hear of disability
and what that looks like and the limitations
and just seeing people with disabilities
sometimes as lesser than or just not as capable.
And all those things kind of bleed into
whether or not someone feels comfortable
with identifying as a disability and having a disability.
And you can have a physical condition
or learning disability and know that you have a limitation
but still not identify as a disabled person.
So that was a big thing for me.
And once I kind of got that, I'm disabled,
I'm part of a community of over a billion people
with disabilities all over the world.
That's a powerful thing to be able to identify yourself
and to know that there are people who have created
every technology that we have experienced.
People with disabilities have created touch phones,
keyboards, iPhones, bicycles.
Those are all created by people with disabilities,
creating, shaping their world to work with their bodies.
And that's a powerful thing to know
that all of our society has been shaped
by people with disabilities.
So my answer to the question is that
I think a lot of students don't identify themselves
as disabled,
they don't go into disability services offices,
they don't recognize they have disabilities
or even get diagnosed with it until later on in life
because of that stigma or the inaccessibility
or whatever it is that's surrounding them.
I think that the first touch point is knowing
that you have a place where you
can go to get those supports
and then knowing that the life isn't over
if you are disabled or you discover you're disabled
later on in life, especially like me,
like I have physical disabilities,
I have invisible disabilities,
I developed some disabilities later on in life,
I was born with others.
Those are different experiences.
So I think the biggest thing is that
students have to know that there's a community
for them on campus.
They have to know that there's other disabled students
like them.
That's the first touch point.
They're never gonna move past
and get the accommodation they need
if they don't know what's available for them
and know what can be adapted to them
and the accommodations that are even available for them.
And once they do get those,
building that community of knowing other people
who have disabilities
and getting to know how they navigate the world,
that's really important to know
that they're not isolated by themselves,
to know that their identity as a person with a disability,
it's just as important as their identity as a woman
or a black person or a Hispanic person
or a first-generation student
and seeing it as a source of empowerment
and a source of community
that contributes to our society and to our schools.
So I think it's really important to see accessibility
as something as a community builder.
You're not seeing it as just following the law
and avoiding a lawsuit.
You're seeing it as bringing in your students
and giving them a place to be in and be who they are.
- I love this.
Let's stop thinking of accessibility
as a compliance problem
and thinking of it as a way to build community.
I love that.
I think I will take that back with me.
Thank you, Jessica.
All right, Keelan and Eddie.
So let's talk a little bit about the career piece
'cause I think we touched on this.
It's definitely an interest of mine.
So now you've got a kid like my son in a job.
He got the job, he got past the interview
thanks to your AI tools.
And there's all this workplace stuff
that requires social skills, right?
There's power dynamics, there's salary negotiation,
there's asking for a promotion,
there's saying no to your boss,
there's dealing with problematic coworkers,
there's taking credit for your work,
there's taking credit for other people's work,
there's all of these things that happen in the workplace
that I know y'all don't know anything about that, right?
For a student with disabilities like my son has,
this can be really challenging.
Can AI help a student like him
or just in general other students
in the career and workplace?
- Yeah, so I wanted to add,
so we create training modules with companies
of all different varieties
and actually the most popular ones
are actually those around durable soft skills actually.
So I think those are massively underestimated.
In fact, the most popular training module
we've deployed throughout the entire
California Community College system
is Google's sending professional emails,
like nothing about like technical anything.
And I started asking faculty,
it's because they felt like
their students can't write emails.
It's been assigned over 100,000 times.
And so that I feel like,
and then when you talk to the HubSpot managers
of those companies, they say the biggest challenges
that they have with the students is not technical.
It's always something related to those durable skills too.
So certainly we have those training materials
and that isn't even related to AI there,
but now we're in an era
where they can get more interactive feedback as well.
So certainly the themes have been popular for a while.
Employer has been on board
and struggling with that for a while.
And now in addition to the training materials
that we've had for a long time,
they're able to get more interactive personalized feedback.
So I'm glad that came up as well
because it's such a critical issue.
And I think that the need to learn AI
is also really important.
A lot of the companies and enterprises
that OpenAI works with,
they are specifically hiring new grads
that have AI experience.
So to teach it early,
to be able to better promote them,
it's not just like using AI to get the job,
but also being able to use AI as a skill
like you might have for productivity is super important.
We see that across every industry.
It's not just education, right?
It's any workforce that people are going into.
If two people have the same technical skills,
but one has more AI use experience,
they're likely gonna get further along
the interview process just because of that alone.
And then that can also lean into
like the soft skill development
and like wellness of that person
going through these processes.
- Is it possible if I can hop in on this question as well?
- Yes, please, please.
- I had an internship this summer on Amazon
as a marketing specialist internship.
And I was actually interning
to market our internship program.
So I'm an intern telling students
to come to Amazon and intern with us,
which is a great opportunity.
And it has a lot of application
to the fact that we're going into schools
and telling students like you have opportunities at Amazon.
One of my big summer projects
went to build a global disability
inclusion marketing strategy.
So thinking about how can we bring in disabled students
into Amazon and tell them that you have a place here.
Up to 30% of students with disabilities
live with disabilities all over the world.
And so that's a big one in three students
can potentially have disabilities.
And so companies need to know how to recruit those students
and show them that they have a place there.
And my internship was, it was on a global team.
So we had team members all over the world,
in China and India and Europe.
One of the big projects that I worked on
how can we make our internship applications more accessible
so that students can come in and apply
and not have any barriers.
And so one of the things that I was working on
with digital accessibility
and how we can make a platform more accessible
for people with like screen readers
and making things more accessible
for people who have like processing disabilities.
And one of the big barriers that I found
was that none of our pages had alt text.
And so if you don't know what alt text is,
it's an image description hidden behind the image
so that if someone uses a screen reader,
they can know what the image is
and it tells them what they're looking at
if they can't visually see it
because they have a blindness.
And so we had over, I believe like 30 different pages
and then like dozens of images on each webpage.
And so I went through and I audited it
and I found that none of them have alt text.
So if a student with a disability
is trying to apply to Amazon,
they're not gonna be able to go through
and actually navigate that.
And so my proposal went to go through
and how to remediate the problem
so that students with disabilities
are not experiencing barriers all along that pipeline
of like learning about Amazon internship programs
all the way through to actually applying
and getting the interview and getting the offer.
And so my estimate originally for remediating the issue
was it would take probably about four months
for it to go through all the pages
and create alt text and images.
Halfway through my program, my internship, I was like,
maybe there's another way to do this.
And so I was looking through all of the learning models
that we have and all of the AI agents
that we have at Amazon
and found that there was actually
an alt text image generator
like it creates alt text, you put in an image,
it will give you an image description.
I was like, this is amazing.
Like maybe this four month process
that I was handing over to somebody else
because my internship wasn't long enough to do it myself,
I could do it myself.
And so I ended up feeding all the images
into this AI agent and putting it through.
What ended up being originally estimated
as a four month process ended up taking a week.
This is the power of accessibility
and using AI to make things accessible.
This experience was the same thing
that you can use in your classes
in all of the things that you do.
If you have a website and you're at a school,
students have to use your portal to apply to your classes.
They have to use Canvas to use your platform.
And if you don't have any descriptions,
it can be really scary to learn how to write them.
You can use AI to help you do that
and remediate those issues before
a student has to complain,
before they have to ask you to fix it.
You can make sure that it's already there
so that they don't have to request it afterwards.
And that's the power of accessibility.
Thinking about how we can change accessibility
so that you don't have to fix things afterwards.
I think that's really important to learn how to do it
and show other students how to do it.
And so when they go into internships
like at Amazon or Google or whatever they wanna do,
they learn how to do that too.
- All right.
- Can I jump in there?
- Yeah, there's a couple questions,
and then I wanna open it to the audience.
So if you have a couple questions, think about it.
All right, let's hear from, actually Eden was first,
and then we're gonna hear from Keelan.
Is that okay?
Go ahead, Eden, you first.
Go ahead, it's okay.
Yeah, yeah.
- Yeah, this is a very big learning experience,
and I'm talking about careers.
I've always wanted to be an educator,
but the part of that intimidates me
is writing the plans, your curriculum,
what you need to do in subjects, all that.
I have all the knowledge here about nursing,
but how am I going to put it into writing?
And it's just like, yesterday, the other day,
it was so eye-opening that I could be able to just speak it
and just tell the bot, a chatbot, whatever,
I don't even know the terminology yet,
and tell them that this is what I want.
So imagine that is like a whole thing of opening the doors
so you can imagine what it is for students.
The other thing is, I feel like what's that,
that when developers and even educators, administration,
have that in mind with your students in,
how do you say it, in developing your curriculum also,
what is being offered.
Maybe because of AI, open up for maybe a general,
what's that, part of the general requirements.
Have someone develop an AI, just intro,
so that we can be up to par.
- Thanks, Eden.
Keelan.
- I was just gonna add to the alt text comment.
So we see a lot of initiatives using the models
for writing code to fix websites
that are not WCAG compliant.
And I think it's a fascinating use case
'cause the models are really good at writing code.
So you can have somebody inspect through it
and there's a lot of accessibility like checkers,
but then if you have the models on the side
that help you rewrite the code and drop in these alt text,
you can go through thousands of pages of online,
like you said, in a week instead of months.
So just, I think, keep that in mind
as you're producing these technologies.
Use the models, not just asking questions,
but actually do some of the development for you
'cause it shortcuts a ton of work.
- Fantastic.
All right, we have time for a couple of questions.
There's a hand up here, go ahead,
and I'll repeat it in the microphone.
(attendee speaks faintly)
How do we find the trainings in Canvas?
- What school, what school are you?
What college are you?
Oh, okay, yeah.
So we've been actually working with Shasta College
and trying to work with their region
to get our app installed within Canvas.
You could help with that.
It's Connect, it's just, once it's there,
then your whole campus can just see all the materials
we just talked about.
There's a few intro to Gen AI content
that have been added to everything
from ESL to agriculture to urban farming.
So there's a good amount of applicability there.
I think we should just sync up afterwards, too.
- All right, other questions?
Yes, in the front.
- [Attendee] I'm trying to establish and institution
with accessibilities and support center on my campus
to help faculty, staff and students learn skills, tools
and any technology to help them make accessibility
and remediation faster.
Through a design with accessibility in mind.
Does anybody in the room have a tool for creating captions
quickly and accurately for video content.
- Creating captions quickly.
And I'm using PowerPoint and you can see
it's not very accurate.
I think when Keelan introduced himself,
it put you down as Kieran Schultz.
So it completely missed your name, by the way.
All right, let's hear suggestions for captioning.
- I mean, I can tell you what we're doing right now
'cause we have to be compliant with that,
is that as far as major models go
for transcribing speech to text,
and Google's unique in that 'cause they own YouTube,
and they transcribe a lot of the text within video
into text, what's being spoken in the video.
So we do have to check that manually as well,
but you just have your interns watch all the videos, too.
But hey, they learn stuff.
But along the way, I think since all the models
have come out, I feel like YouTube's speech to text
have improved a lot as well.
So you do have to do some double checks.
But I feel like that is probably one of the easier ways
to be compliant.
If you use Vimeo for your content,
there are ways where you can have
that manually transcribed as well.
So there's a couple ways to go at it
depending on which video player that you use
and how much time and resources you wanna put into it.
- Kind of stole my answer.
I think it depends on the source and platform
that you wanna use for that one.
Like internally at OpenAI, we use our models
to break apart a video, take out that audio transcript,
and then we run it through our text to,
or speech to text model effectively
that generates the text for us.
That's not something that you can just turn key.
You know, it's a development process.
But we do see a lot of platforms engaging with the models
to do that kind of activity.
And that's where like a really
good accuracy comes into play
like the fact that this one messed up my name
shouldn't do that.
And if you have a model that's like plugged into
like your SIS system, for example,
and it knows who the speakers are,
then it should be able to translate better
because it has more context of what's actually happening.
And I think that's where we're gonna see
a lot of these translation apps go towards
is have a better understanding of who's speaking
and then when they transcribe,
it has a more context of what it's transcribing to.
- Speaking of that, I went to my son's graduation in May.
And the students that were graduating,
you know how they always mangle the names,
especially the names that are not American sounding names
or English names, right?
So the students said their names into a microphone
like behind a curtain.
And then an AI voice that sounded like a white male
speaking standardized English would then replay that.
And so none of the names were mangled,
but it was interesting that they still had to sort of
put it in his voice.
You know, there was still this standardization
that was happening.
Great questions.
We have time for one more before I let you out
to go grab your lunches.
Yes, back there.
- [Attendee] This might be everyone's thing
we're talking about RSI.
But this question of Regular Substantive Interaction,
which is required of our online courses for accreditation.
I'm just curious on what your thoughts of whether,
or to what extent AI can help or hinder
that requirement for Regular Substantive Interaction
between relationships.
- Yeah, and just for some context,
RSI, Regular Substantive Interaction
is an accreditation requirement.
It's a federal requirement for asynchronous online courses.
And so what we're finding is it's hard.
It's hard to show that level of engagement
in our asynchronous online courses.
So how does AI help us with that?
That's your question.
Or not, or hinder that.
How about our students?
Any thoughts about engagement
in your asynchronous online courses?
I know, Jessica, you've taken a lot
and you've probably seen the gamut
of engagement in those classes.
- Yeah.
I think one of the big things
is AI shouldn't replace that contact with a professor.
And I think it's really easy to think of it that way
because one of the first things that we hear about AI
is that it's a time-saver.
One of the biggest time-consuming things
is communication, especially if you're writing things.
And so I think that's one of the biggest things
is making sure that you're not over-automating
your processes and that if you are automating,
that you're auditing what you're automating.
Just because if you're not double-checking
what you're creating,
it can come out completely inaccurate,
it can not have the right context,
or it might not actually be appropriate
for what that student needs.
Because students with disabilities
have so many different kinds of disabilities,
both from learning disabilities to physical disabilities,
and it's gonna present in different ways.
Even if you have someone with the exact same disability,
certain students will have the ability to do one thing
and the other student won't,
even if they have that same disability.
So I think the other thing is that
when you are building anything for students,
it's actually testing it with students with disabilities.
You have to make sure that anything that you're creating
has that voice from students themselves
and from people with disabilities themselves.
Otherwise, you're not getting that
authentic lived experience
and you're gonna find there's a lot of gaps
that you hadn't really thought about
because you can't replicate that lived experience
without having it yourself.
I hope that helps.
- That's great.
- I did wanna add real quick the perspective
as an adjunct there too,
which most of the college's faculty are.
We get a lot of questions from students.
So I would just drive like an hour or something,
and then I'd buy emails from students.
So I wouldn't worry, I mean, I wouldn't worry so much
that faculty are gonna lean on like a bot
or something too much.
I actually think it helps because there's more questions
than most faculty I feel like can answer,
especially since most are adjuncts.
So while I think you do need to monitor
and make sure the RSI is gonna be okay,
I actually think that it helps more than hinders.
Granted, we do need to see more
of how this is gonna play out,
but I actually don't think,
I think it's gonna help students more than it hurts.
- I attempted to work with a vendor partner and I failed,
but this is what we would like to see in a tool
as a faculty member.
If I could log into my online class
and then get a little nudge like Marina, be careful,
your student Keelan has not been engaged
and has not like opened his assignments.
It's been three weeks, you might wanna check on him.
You might wanna also check on Eden
because she only interacts with
one person in the classroom,
another student, she might need to be put in a group
where she could learn more about her peers,
something like that, like if AI could be my friend
in the classroom to help me, I don't know,
that's just a thought for our partners.
- Oh, we have an AI friend for faculty now.
It was actually designed by a De Anza student.
It is a rodent named Capy.
So for those of you who know what capybaras are,
world's largest rodent, and to make it,
now we talked about how to make it not fearful,
so we asked our intern from De Anza,
what would be the best mascot for this chatbot?
She said capybara.
So now living within Canvas,
you can ask your capybara questions about,
hey, what sort of, what fits within my course
that they wouldn't normally know
because we can get data from the other campuses,
like why would anybody know that an ESL class
in Santa Ana College used HubSpot,
how to create professional LinkedIn profile,
or in Irvine Valley College, they use Google,
sending professional emails in another ESL class.
So let's say College of the Siskiyous,
I think somebody would wanna know that too,
and then the world's largest rodent
could advise you on that in Canvas.
So that's one way, I guess,
we're creating a friendly faculty advisor.
- So we are at time, it's 11:57.
Could I, would it be okay if we stuck around
in case audience members wanna come here and chat with us?
So could I just get a round of applause
for our amazing panelists?
(audience applauding)
Thank you so much, and enjoy your lunch,
and we will stick around if folks wanna come up
and talk individually with our amazing panelists.
(people chatting)